Guide to the Le Van Merchant Burt family papers, [ca.1860-1924]
Burt, Le Van Merchant family papers, [ca.1860-1924]
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Le Van Merchant Burt family papers, [ca.1860-1924]
2327
Le Van Merchant Burt, 1875-1971.
2 cubic ft.
Letters, diaries, papers, contracts, scrapbooks, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Letters and documents relating to the Civil War, various business ventures, and political activities.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Letters and documents relating to the service of Burt's father, Captain Franklin Burt (1841-1924) in the 89th Regiment, New York Volunteers, including letters from family and friends in Corbettsville, New York, from other officers, and from pension authorities after the Civil War; also, diaries for 1861-63; and later letters regarding Burt's search for information on a brother killed in the war. There are letters from old comrades, war reminiscences, and photographs including survivors of the 89th New York Volunteer Infantry Regiment Reunion - 1914. Other papers relate to Burt's ownership of Calvert Tannery at Mannington, West Virginia; the Burt Oil Company of West Virginia and Kentucky; and the Burt Mines and Milling Company of Colorado, and include business letters, tanning contracts, stockholders' lists, scrapbooks, and photographs of mining operations. Other materials document his post of Masonic Grand Master of West Virginia, and his candidacy for governor on the Prohibition ticket in 1892, including manuscript temperance speeches. There is also a microfilm copy of Franklin Burt's autobiography.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Burt, Le Van Merchant, 1875-1971.; Burt, Franklin, 1841-1924.; Burt Mines and Milling Company.; Burt Oil Company.; Calvert Tannery.; Prohibition Party.; United States. Army. New York Volunteers, 89th.
Subjects:
Freemasonry.; Mines and mineral resources.; Mineral industries.; Mining engineering.; Petroleum industry and trade.; Politics and government--West Virginia.; Tanning.; Businessmen.
Places:
United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; West Virginia.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Photoprints.; Reminiscences.; Scrapbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Link to a PDF copy of a description of Franklin Burt's autobiography.
- 1860-1864 (Box 1)
- 1865-c.1896 (Box 2)
- 1897-1924 (Box 3)
- Pamphlets (Box 3)
- Broadsides (Box 3)
- Newspapers (Box 3)
- Maps (Box 3)
- Grand Army of the Republic (Box 3)
- undated material concerning the Civil War (Box 3)
- undated miscellanea (Box 3)
- undated material concerning religion and politics (Box 3)
- Accounts and Diaries (Box 3)
- Photographs: Includes a photo of the reunion of the 89th New York Volunteer Infantry Regiment (Box 3)
- Scrapbooks Nos. 1 and 3(of 4) (Box 4)
- Scrapbooks Nos. 2 and 4(of 4) (Box 5)
- General Orders No. 5 from Headquarters, Elmira Depot, N.Y. Volunteers, Elmira, N.Y., Aug. 9, 1861, 1 (Map-case ?)
- Invoice of Ordinance and Ordinance Stores turned over to Frank Burt at Washington, D.C., Jan. 4, 1862; two copies, both duplicates, 2 (Map-case ?)
- Return of Ordinance and Ordinance Stores, Jan. 14, 1963, by Frank Burt opposite Fredericksburg, Va., 3 (Map-case ?)
- Return of Ordinance and Ordinance Stores, Mar. 31, 1863, by Frank Burt at Suffolk, Va., 4 (Map-case ?)
- Return of Ordinance and Ordinance Stores, July 17, 1863, by Frank Burt near Portsmouth, Va., 5 (Map-case ?)
- Quarterly return of clothing, camp and garrison equipage, Sept. 30, 1863, by Frank Burt at Folly Island, S.C., 6 (Map-case ?)
- Clothing list for non-commissioned officers, artificers, musicians, and privates received July 1863-Sept. 1863, 7 (Map-case ?)
- Inventory and Inspection Report of unserviceable clothing, camp and garrison equipage, Oct. 2, 1863, 8 (Map-case ?)
- Certification of loss, witnessed Oct. 15, 1863, for articles lost Oct. 28, 1862, 9 (Map-case ?)
- Certification of loss, witnessed Oct. 15, 1863, for articles lost Dec. 21, 1862, 10 (Map-case ?)
- Quarterly return of Ordinannces and Ordinance Stores, Oct. 20, 1863, by Frank Burt at Folly Island, S.C., 11 (Map-case ?)
- Clothing list for non-commissioned officers, artificers, musicians, and privates receieved Oct. 1863, 12 (Map-case ?)
- Monthly return of clothing, camp and garrison equipage, Nov. 3, 1863, by Frank Burt at Folly Island, S.C., 13 (Map-case ?)
- Certification of loss witnessed, Nov. 17, 1863, for articles lost Sept. 17, 1862, 14 (Map-case ?)
- Certificate of loss witnessed, Nov. 17, 1863, for articles lost July 3, 1863, 15 (Map-case ?)
- Clothing list for non-commissioned officers, artificers, musicians, and privates receieved Nov. 1863, 16 (Map-case ?)
- Monthly report of clothing, camp and garrison equipage, Dec. 1, 1863, by Frank Burt at Folly Island, S.C., 17 (Map-case ?)
- Clothing list for non-commissioned officers, artificers, musicians, and privates receieved on Dec. 20, 1863, 18 (Map-case ?)
- Monthly report of clothing, camp and garrison equipage, Jan. 5, 1864, by Frank Burt, Folly Island, S.C., 19 (Map-case ?)
- Clothing list for non-commissioned officers, artificers, musicians, and privates received on Jan. 12, 1864, 20 (Map-case ?)
- Monthly report of clothing, camp and garrison equipage, Jan. 29, 1864, by Frank Burt, Folly Island, S.C., 21 (Map-case ?)